guys this looks like a fun one this was
posted by my math Solutions we've got
three rectangles and it wants us to know
the area of this rectangle in the middle
so first let's focus on this gray
rectangle area of it is going to be base
times height this two centimeters only
goes to here so let's make the rest of
this X and since the bottom is X plus 2
the top would also be X plus two and we
could change the base into X plus two
now for the height we know this part is
three and for the unknown part let's
call it Z and since this is three and
this is only two we need to make this Z
plus one so that both Heights are equal
to Z plus three and now let's bring
these rectangles back let's get rid of
the question mark and bring this
rectangle inside here and let's focus on
this rectangle here this 26 centimeter
squared refers to this backwards L shape
but we don't know the gray area so we'll
call that a we know that a plus 26 is
going to be equal to the area of the
whole rectangle which is 7 times 6. 7
times 6 is 42 and after we subtract 26
from both sides we find out that a is
equal to 16. and a is this rectangle
made up of x times e so really we found
out that x times Z equals 16. and that's
really what's most important here and
now let's extend this other rectangle
and focus on it if we call the area of
this region B we know that b plus 36 is
going to be equal to 7 times 8. 7 times
8 is 56 and after we subtract 36 from
both sides we get D is equal to 20. and
this B is also equal to the base times
the height or in other words x times Z
plus one and that's really what's
important here now we have a system of
equations we have two variables and two
equations let's get X by itself for both
of these for this top one we'll divide
both sides by Z these Z's will cancel
each other out leaving us with just x
equals 16 over Z and for this one let's
divide both sides by Z plus one and then
these will cancel leaving us with just x
equals a 20 over Z plus one so we have
found that X is equal to 16 over Z well
in the place of this x down here I'm
going to plug in 16 over Z and now we
have a proportion we can solve this by
cross multiplying we have 16x times Z
plus 1 is equal to this 20 times Z and
then we can distribute the 16. 16 times
Z is 16z and then 16 times 1 is 16. and
on this side we have 20 Z and then we
can subtract 16z from both sides on the
left hand side these are gone so we just
have 16 and on the right hand side we
have 4z we can divide both sides by 4
and we have 4 equals z and then we can
rewrite that as Z equals four so since
we know the Z equals 4 I'm going to plug
in 4 for this Z right here and 16
divided by 4 is 4. so we know x equals 4
so we can plug in 4 for this X and we
know Z equals 4 so we can plug in 4 for
this Z here 4 plus 2 is equal to 6 and
here 4 plus 3 is equal to 7 and 6 times
7 is equal to 42. we have now found the
value of our question mark it's 42. so
for this question mark let's put in 42
centimeters squared that is the answer
to our question and it's already got a
box around it how exciting